15 sept 2007
  first release, converted from a version in VBasic6, written in 2005

28 oct 2007
- now displays characters x00 to x1f as *
- commandline can now be more than "lrecl" chars long
- displays contents of not-active window correctly, after partial overlay
- now accepts: DO expression; ................; END
- added AUTOSAVE setting
- added RESERVED lines
- Filename will stay in lowercaseletters if invoked from explorer
- returncode from MACRO was always 0
- "do i=1 to 0" now works well
- "do i=1 to 9 for 0" now works well
- MCopy now copies multiple lines
- REPLACE now redraws the modified line
- Added FIND and FINDUP commands and RING and LSCREEN extract-inf 
- Removed nasty parsing error in comples conditions 
- Undo respects empty inserted lines now
- Added GET, PUT and RESET commands
- Added " and "" line commands
- Allow PASTE on Bot of file

26 nov 2007
- Correcting UNDO behaviour, some "automatic" undo's were accidentally introduced
- Added info to fatal error messages to better determine the type of error

5 dec 2007
- catch error "file not found" in case of calling a non-existing windows application
- build a version that traces all activity, used to communicate errors to the author
- case upper/mixed was implemented reverse

10 dec 2007
- Had to change string.ToUpper in string.ToUpper(CultureInfo) because in Turkish and Azeri
  the lowercase letter i does not translate into the upppercase I but into a local İ, 
  which completely confused my programming logic. Thanks Riza Dindir for finding that out.
- added a PRINT command to print the visible part of the file
- added VB6ToVBNet.rex to change old VB6 string manipulation to .Net. Eg. Len(s) to s.Length()
- if screen had been shifted left of right, the linecommand did not appear anymore

3 jan 2008 
- Split the source in two. Created a new RxLib with the Rexx stuff, so it may be used in any application.
- calling a windows program without parameters failed with a Length-error

17 jan 2008
- allowed synonyms for many "SET" commands, to ommit the "set"
- selection with the mouse, mCOPY, mCUT and mPASTE did not respect the visible part,
  if RIGHT n had been used.
- VERIFY right margin is calculated wrong by LEFT n

31 mrt 2008 
- Added function REGEXP to Rexx: r = RegExp("stem.","text to process","regular expression")
  r = true if there was at least one match; Stem.1, Stem.2, etc. contain the mnatching parts, stem.0 the number of elements in stem
- Added VB6ToVBNet command to change most of the VB6 stringfunctions to the .Net version
- DD line command does not allow paging. 
- EXECIO without '(OPTIONS' might go into a system error "object not set".
- SORT contains a useless message about n° of lines sorted

30 apr 2008
- LOCATE /string/ & /other/ : my search-algorithm was absolutely wrong!
- SET CASE was not always coherent
- Cursor on wrong line, if selected area was deleted and excluded lines on the screen

15 may 2008
- SORT needed LINEND OFF to work properly

8 jun 2008 
- Compose char with ALT-nnn and NumLock On now works well
- Delete selected area with lines not on screen give wrong cursor position
- LOCATE and SET STAY OFF results always in rc=0

5 sept 2008 
- The starting position for selecting with the mouse is now preserved, also
  if you point above toe original point. Until now, this higher line became the new starting
  point.
- Ctrl-C from a portion of the commandline, blanks the line itself. wrong

15 oct 2008 
- Added LINEND OFF in SPLTJOIN.
- wrong rc when replaing a selected part of the text
- added line from and to in Change command (Present in TSO-Edit, not in CMS-Xedit)

17 nov 2008 
- Added message when LOCATE finds a string in the invisible part of the text.
- Added SET and EXTRACT MSGMODE ON/OFF

22 dec 2008
- Command is ignored, if file contains inserted empty lines
- Paste ignores empty lines

01 mar 2009 
- in VISTA the cursor and selected parts of text displays in wrong position on the screen
- in VISTA selecting lines below the screen fails because of the speed ofd the scrolling

27 mar 2009
- Messages provoke an error screen
- CINSERT starts 1 pos to far in line
- Added keys for { and } in Ctrl-( and Ctrl-) creating new macro CInsCursor
- Added a translate tab-char to 1 to 4 spaces on screen

15 may 2009 
- intercept drawing error on some lines of the screen, for unknown reasons
- changed commandline separator from ( to ? to allow names with () in it to be opened

2 june 2009
- I believe to having solved the "wrong parameter" in the screen display

22 june 2009
- Search for macro's: 1st in path of file, 2nd: in installation 

30 july 2009
- changed way of determining . or , as dec separator: problems in Norwegian
- if file did not end with Cr of CrLf, the last character was lost.
- Pasting added a nasty space at the beginning of a line, sometimes

30 aug 2009
- added FndBracket macro under alt-9 to find close bracket(s)

6 dec 2009, ver 2.1.0.16
- added some more unprintable characters as a dot
- call rexx from rexx lead in Stack overflow, made a temp fix, eliminating separate RxLib

28 febr 2010
- modified SORT.rex, Windows 7 denies access to c:\ directory

21 april 2011
- Added support for Unicode files
- Added SET UNICODE NO as an OPTION to allow editting Unicode-files as Ascii

8 may 2011
- Converted to .Net V4
- XeditPc now shows neatly, wether the last sourceline contained a CrLf, by adding an empty line at the bottom
- Solved old problem with "Rexx in Rexx" Command handling. You may now nest calls in Rexx to Rexx.
- Rexx needed CrLf at end, not anymore
- Distribute RxLib as seperate dll, now that problems with Rexx are solved
- Added Extract /TEMP/ to obtain the windows temporary path name

3 june 2011
- Solved "pointer before beginning of file" while saving

31 july 2011
- Solved "index outside bounds" in Find command

12 oct 2011
- modified sort command, to use TEMP as workspace
- before closing, change window size to show save dialog (error in WIN7 when maximized)
- show window after opening a file in front
- added READ CMDLINE command
- added some RPG-III specific commands
  
7 january 2012 
- added SET TABS on/off nn nn nn nn 
- implemented PRESERVE and RESTORE
- added MACRO Record / Stop with right mouseclick
- added PLAY macroname / filename to play a recorded macro.
 
12 march 2012 
- VERIFY HEX with sourceline shorter, ends in display error

15 march 2012 
- Added support for AltGr-Shift type keys es. {
- suppressed message "No command for CTRL-... or ALT-..." if ... not ascii (> 128) 
- Added EXTRACT APPLICATIONPATH to find where Xedit is installed 
- Added LSE-type support, Language Sensitive Editor once on Dec Vms, now on HP,
  allows templates and expansion, aiding you to write in a rather unknown language. 
  As a sample I add the REX.LSE file for writing REXX.
  new commands: Exp (expand token, ctrl-E), ExpD (delete [] around optional source, CTRL-D,
  ExpW (remove optional part, CTRL-W) and ExpN (jump to next token, CTRL-TAB)
   
28 april 2012 
- John showed me a severe error when putting CMDLINE on top. Hope to have resolved it. 
- added msg with nr. of occ. in change 
- avoid duplicate messagges 
- End-key at end now returns to start of line
  
16 jun 2012 
- msg File R/O when existing file in system directory, may be not R/O 
  
15 sept 2012 
- Paste did not respect SET ZONE 
  
10 oct 2012 
- Added Immediate REXX while using interactive trace, when paused you can write immediate Rexx, assigns, say, etc 
- Added SET REXXTRACE ON/OFF to activate debug for rexx-scripts
  
16 nov 2012 
- corrected error in macro record for ctrl-keys 

18 jan 2013
- Paste when a source was selected, ended up somewhere at random

01 jun 2013
- macro record of anu Fnn-key fails

04 aug 2013
- fixed an error in the RexxLib, parsing of ; at end of line

05 aug 2013
- finished LSE macro's, EXPand, EXPDelete, EXPInclude, EXPNext, REX.LSE
  
02 jan 2014 
- Change command of last char on a line failed 
 
05 febr 2014 
- added a Bulk rename command as example of how to use DOS commands 
  
16 june 2014 
- added right scrollbar to scroll vertically through the file. Repositioning has a .2 sec delay to avoid 
  constant painting. 
 
20 jul 2014
- introduced targets like IBM's XEDIT (targetnames in uppercase only and only one per line)
  and allow for a command on the locate command eg: :8 change /a/b/ 3
  LOCATE, DELETE and CHANGE now use targets, as IBM's version does
   
10 sept 2014 
- Writing a new file in a (usually R/O map) is now checked afterwards, not predicted. 
   
27 sept 2014 
- DOWN command forgot to register RC
- Rex not found in other Rex destroyed call-stack
   
4 oct 2014 
- Added full UTF8 support, adding options to indicate UTF8, ASCII or UNICODE
- disallow to modify Top of File
- respond to CANCEL key on commandline
 
7 nov 2014 
- If a file is ASCII with characters > 127, but opened as UTF8, windows inserts xFDFE characters, now treated as ASCII 
- Unicode characters in Rexx script treated as ASCII if file is UTF8 coded and Unicode if UTF16 coded
- added b and e to change command (change at beginning or end of line)
- fixed some issues in ALL macro
  
19 dec 2014 
- fixed erroneous parameter passing in nested routine-calls 
 
25 jan 2015 
- command = with parameter caused Program Stack overflow    

13 mar 2015
- added SET REXXPATH to indicate searchorder of REXX files   

1 apr 2015
- Rexx ignored continuation lines    
- Rexx omitted parameter ruined stack    
 
4 may 2015
- Added conditional macro for REX on ESC key.
 
8 feb 2017
- LINES() function returns incorrect nr. of lines remaining, corrected
- a literal index for a stem was ignored.
 
30 apr 2017
- corrected display of filename in title  
    
18 jun 2017
- LINES now returns 0 if a file does not exist
  LINES is now ANSI: 2nd parameter C (count lines) or N (report EOF only). Default C
- External routines now can return strings as a return value 
- added some string functions  
     
11 dec 2017
- added all missing logical operators
- corrected the incorrect way expressions were parsed 

14 aug 2019
- click on cmdline moves cursor backward until a character is met
- dubbel macro (eliminate double lines) extended with starting and ending position

23 nov 2019
- message not always shown in large scripts

21 dec 2019
- avoid frequent screenupdates when using multiple XEDIT in a script
- better signal when quote is missing

17 jan 2020
- dispay statement in error when value not numeric
- unexposed variable in procedure not correctly passed to internal routines 

6 febr 2020
- allow rex scripts to be coded in UTF8 or Unicode
- parse syntax verified better, had an error
- message if utf8 file contains ansi chars > 128, won't save

30 mar 2020 (Corona virus week)
- refactored Hex views and editing
- PF4 now goes to next tablocation if tabs are set

18 apr
- ignore UTF8 BOM

30 apr
- external recursive rexx shared variables between them

23 may 2020
- unified external commands in all .rex files
- verified all functions
- added CONTAINS function

30 july 2020
- display of UNICODE/UTF not always correct

09 sept 2020
- rewrote SORT to cope with UFT8

01 nov 2020
- colored line with cursor on it 

19 dec 2020 
- added recent files list
- allowed X'..' X".." '..'X and ".."X in hexadecimal change so Edit and Rexx are congruent
- added "lower" to parse statement, to parse all in lowercase
- repaired DROP of uninitialized group

8 jan 2021
- changed the way parameters are transferred from one to another routine

26 apr 2021
- added support to change colors of 
   Textline, Textline with cursor on it, Textline background 
   Linenumbers, Curline as defined for commands, Linenumbers background     
   Selected text, selected background      
   Command line, command line background 
   cursor symbol (line or bar)
   see help file for syntax or System profil.rex for defaults

28 apr 2021
-  removed destruction of text when edditing 2 or more files in a ring
-  scrollbar larger
-  save/quit window must be answered, not closed
-  color for screen background
-  position of reserved lined can be a negative number (counts from bottom)

 
Known errors:
  
If you switch from Xedit to another application, on return the screen displays only the
first line (the statistics line). Click on taskbar to hide and show, to repaint the screen.

If you hover the mouse over the windows taskbar, you also might get the blank screen.

If the first screenline is an Excluded type, scrolling up may cause extra eXcludes, not all true

Saving an UTF8 file with ANSI chars > 128 (accented vowels, f.i.) won't save these, specify ENCODE ASCII
                                             